rockhall.com 2019-04-01

# Privacy policy | Rock & Roll Hall of Fame

#### PRIVACY POLICY

The [www.rockhall.com](https://www.rockhall.com/) website (the “Website) and Rock & Roll Hall of Fame social media accounts and mobile applications (collectively, the “Services”) are operated by The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum, Inc. (the “Rock Hall”), located at 1100 Rock & Roll Boulevard, Cleveland, Ohio 44114-1022.  We take the private nature of your personal information seriously, and this Privacy Policy describes how we treat the information we collect when you use the Services.  Please read this notice very carefully.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected at (a) any annexes or off-site or traveling exhibits, (b) the physical Rock Hall Store located at the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Rock Hall and operated by FYE (excluding information conveyed for purposes of activating a membership purchased through the store); or (c) by the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame Foundation, Inc.

BY USING THE SERVICES, YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION ACCORDING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AS WELL AS OTHER COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY.  BY UPLOADING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE SERVICES You warrant that you have the right to transfer such information outside your country and into the United States.

**Children Under 18 Years of Age**

The Rock Hall does not knowingly collect any information from children under 13 years old through the Website. Anyone under 18 years old may only access the Website or disclose information to the Rock Hall under the direct guidance and supervision of a parent or guardian. The Rock Hall believes that parents should supervise their children's online activities and should consider using parental control tools available from online services and software manufacturers that help provide a safe online environment for children to work within. These tools can also prevent children from disclosing personal information without parental permission. If the parent or guardian of a child under 13 believes that the child has provided us with any information, the parent or guardian of that child should contact us if they want this information deleted from our files. If the Rock Hall obtains knowledge from any source that it has information about a child under 13 in retrievable form in its files, we will delete that information from our existing files.

**The Information we collect**

As specified below, the Rock Hall may collect information about you that can be used to identify you (“Personal Information”), information necessary to process a purchase (“Purchase Information”) and information about your use of the Website gathered from cookies or similar technology, your use of Rock Hall-provided wifi or information gathered from your use of a Rock Hall wristband (“Other Information”) (collectively, “Information”).

_**Personal Information**_

When you sign up for or use the Services, you may voluntarily give us certain information about yourself.  This can include name, username, profile photo, email address, city, state, gender and any other information you provide us.  If you are using the Services on your mobile device, you may also choose to provide us with location data. 

_**Purchase Information**_

You may be requested to provide Purchase Information when you seek to purchase items (such as a membership or merchandise from our e-commerce store), make a donation, register for an activity or purchase tickets or similar transactions.  Purchase Information includes your credit card information, billing information and shipping information.  Your Purchase Information will be used only as needed to process your transaction and may be stored in our systems after your transaction is complete so that we can track and service your order, address any issues or questions that may arise with respect to your transaction or research our programs, services and other offerings. 

_**Other Information**_

Like most website operators, the Rock Hall collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request when visitors use the Website. The Rock Hall’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how our visitors use the Services. From time to time, the Rock Hall or its service providers may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate (for example, by publishing a report on trends in the usage of Rock Hall’s Services or service provider’s platforms).  The Rock Hall also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses and may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to the Services. For instance, the Rock Hall may monitor the Website to help identify threats or monitor what areas of the Website in which visitors spend significant time. 

In addition to log data, we may also collect information about the device you are using to access the Services, including the type of device, the operating system, device settings, device identifiers and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings.  To learn more about the information your device makes available to us, please review the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider.

Like many websites, the Website may use “cookies” or similar technologies to collect information.  A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. The Rock Hall may use cookies or other technology to help identify and track visitors, their usage of the Website, and their Website access preferences. Website visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the Website, with the drawback that certain features of Website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

By wearing a Rock Hall wristband or if you use the Rock Hall’s wifi service while onsite at the Rock Hall’s premises, the Rock Hall may collect information about you, your wireless devices and your visit (such as areas of the museum you visit and how much time you spent in a particular area).

**HOw do we use your information**

We use the Information we collect to provide you full access and functionality of the Services.  Accordingly, your Information may be used for the following purposes: (i) to provide and improve our services, features and content; (ii) to administer your use of our services and accounts; (iii) to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Services; (iv) to better understand your needs and interests; (v) to fulfill requests or to respond to questions or comments you may make; (vi) to personalize your experience; (vii) to provide you with announcements, notifications and advertisements related to your interests and use of the Services and other communications such as electronic newsletters, promotional e-mails or similar messaging; (viii) to provide service announcements; (ix) to protect against users seeking to hack into the Services; and (x) to assess the level of general interest in the Services.

**With Whom Do We Share Your Information?**

The Rock Hall may share your Information with certain third parties such as our agents, service providers and other representatives acting or collecting such information on our behalf.  The third parties with whom we conduct business are authorized to use your Information to perform the service for which they are hired or to conduct research and analysis, and they are required to take reasonable measures to ensure your Information is secure. 

On occasion, we contract with trusted third-party providers who may receive your Information (excluding credit card numbers) to conduct anonymized aggregate analyses of the data.  Except as otherwise provided in this policy we do not disclose or sell your individualized Information to other parties. 

_**Promotional Packages and Educational Programs**_

When you register for an educational program or promotional package (for example, a ticket package that offers you admission to the Rock Hall and to another attraction or hotel stay), your Information, including your Purchase Information, may be shared with the businesses or educational institutions identified by name in the promotional package or educational program materials as well as the online vendors facilitating such transactions. This is required to complete your reservation or registration in the promotional package or educational program and to provide information to each business or educational institution identified by name in the promotion.  This Privacy Policy only governs your use of the Website identified in the first paragraph and the Rock Hall is not responsible for the content or privacy practices employed by any third party.  Please be aware that third party websites may include a Rock Hall logo, may be linked to the Websites or may otherwise appear to be affiliated with the Rock Hall but will not be governed by this policy.  For this reason, we encourage you to review the privacy policies of those third parties before disclosing any Information to or through them. 

_**Nonprofit Cultural Institutions**_

We reserve the right to share your Information (excluding credit card numbers) with other nonprofit cultural institutions. If you do not want to have your Information used in this way, you may send an e-mail message containing your name, e-mail address and postal address to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#8befe4e5e4fff8e3eaf9eecbf9e4e8e0e3eae7e7a5e4f9ec).

 _ **Additional Disclosures**_

In the event that the Rock Hall enters into a business transition, such as a merger with or an acquisition by another company, or a sale of a portion of or all of its assets, your Information may be among the assets that are transferred or disclosed in connection with such a transaction. 

From time to time, we may be required to share Information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may share certain Information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property and safety of others and ourselves. 

#### SECURITY

We are committed to protecting your Information. We regularly test our facilities and use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.  

**How do I inform the Rock Hall of my Preferences?**

_**Marketing Communications**_  
If you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from or related to the Rock Hall, let us know by using whichever of the following methods is appropriate under the circumstances: 

  * Follow the directions on the e-mail or direct mail communication you receive from us; 
  * Call 216-781-ROCK (7625) with your request and current contact information; 
  * Send an e-mail with your request and current contact information to: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#5d0d2f342b3c3e24103c333c3a382f1d2f323e36353c313173322f3a); or 
  * Send a letter with your request and current contact information to:  
The Rock & Roll Hall of Fame  
c/o General Counsel’s Office  
1100 Rock and Roll Boulevard  
Cleveland, Ohio 44114-1022 

If you send an e-mail or letter request, please be sure to include your full name, address, phone number and e-mail address, as well as the specific changes you would like to have made. This will ensure we correctly identify you in our systems and accurately process your request.

The Rock Hall will take the appropriate steps to modify your preferences with respect to our marketing communications. Due to production, mailing and system timelines, it may take some time to process your request. Until your requested change takes effect, you may still receive communications from us. If you send us your request by regular mail, please allow extra time for us to receive your notice.

Please note: Although you may have opted not to receive communications, you may still receive business-related communications such as order confirmations, product recall notices, membership information, or other communications that are necessary to complete your transaction. 

_**Consent and Modifications to Privacy Policy**_

By using the Services, providing Information to the Rock Hall, utilizing our free wifi service, buying tickets via our website or from one of our partners and/or visiting [www.rockhall.com](https://www.rockhall.com/), you signify your consent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use, please do not use our website, the Services, or provide your Information to us or a partner. 

The Rock Hall reserves the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time and will update this page to reflect the date of the last update. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued provision of Information to us and/or use of Services following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. The date of the last update is located at the bottom of this privacy policy. 

_**Your California Privacy Rights**_

A business subject to California Civil Code section 1798.83 is required to disclose to its California customers, upon request, the identity of any third parties to whom the business has disclosed personal information within the previous calendar year, along with the type of personal information disclosed, for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please send an email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1343617a6572706a5e727d7274766153617c70787b727f7f3d7c6174).

_**Contact Us: Questions, Updating, Correcting and Changing Your Information**_

The Rock Hall is committed to undertaking measures that protect the confidentiality and security of your Information. If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, or would like to be removed from our mailing lists, update your Information, or change your preferences about the information you receive from us, please contact the Rock Hall directly. Click here to email us, call us at 216-781-ROCK (7625) or use the postal address below.

The Rock & Roll Hall of Fame  
c/o General Counsel’s Office  
1100 Rock & Roll Boulevard  
Cleveland, Ohio 44114-1022 

LAST UPDATED:  MARCH 2018

4819-2805-7695, v. 1
